let begginerQue = [
  {
    'question':'1. [7π/12]',
    'ans1':'135°',
    'ans2':'105°',
    'ans3':'35°',
    'ans4':'15°',
    'answer':'105°',
    'class':'inactive',
    'class2':'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'2. sin[31π/4]',
    'ans1':'1/√2',
    'ans2':'√3/2',
    'ans3':'1',
    'ans4':'0',
    'answer':'√3/2',
    'class':'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'3. sec(-420°)',
    'ans1':'1',
    'ans2':'0',
    'ans3':'√3/2°',
    'ans4':'2',
    'answer':'2',
    'class':'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'4. cos5x+cos3x',
    'ans1':'2cos4xcosx',
    'ans2':'-2sin6x',
    'ans3':'2sin6xsinx',
    'ans4':'cos2x-cos8x',
    'answer':'2cos4xcosx',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'5. Which among the following waves is used for communication by artificial satellites?',
    'ans1':'The frequency of 101 series',
    'ans2':'Radio waves',
    'ans3':'A. M.',
    'ans4':'Microwaves',
    'answer':'Microwaves',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'6. When the speed of a car is doubled then what should be the braking force of the car to stop it at the same distance?',
    'ans1':'two times',
    'ans2':'four times',
    'ans3':'half',
    'ans4':'one fourth',
    'answer':'four times',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'7. The mass of a star is two times the mass of the Sun. How will it come to an end?',
    'ans1':'Neutron Star',
    'ans2':'Blackhole',
    'ans3':'White Dwarf',
    'ans4':'Red Giant',
    'answer':'Neutron Star',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'8. Which of the following statements is true when we see a rainbow?',
    'ans1':'We must face the sun and view it through the raindrops',
    'ans2':'The Sun remains behind us and we face the raindrops',
    'ans3':'In a light rainfall, we will face the Sun',
    'ans4':'The sky remains clear and the sun is at a lower position in the sky',
    'answer':'The Sun remains behind us and we face the raindrops',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'9. Cement is made hard by:',
    'ans1':'dehydration',
    'ans2':'hydration and dissociation of water',
    'ans3':'Dissociation of water',
    'ans4':'Polymerisation',
    'answer':'hydration and dissociation of water',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'10. What happens when a chemical bond is formed?',
    'ans1':'energy is always absorbed',
    'ans2':'energy is always released',
    'ans3':'more energy is released than is absorbed',
    'ans4':'energy is neither released nor absorbed',
    'answer':'energy is always absorbed',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'11. Milk of Magnesia is a suspension of:',
    'ans1':'magnesium sulphate',
    'ans2':'magnesium carbonate',
    'ans3':'magnesium hydroxide',
    'ans4':'magnesium chloride',
    'answer':'magnesium hydroxide',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'12. The ratio of pure gold in 18-carat gold is:',
    'ans1':'60%',
    'ans2':'75%',
    'ans3':'80%',
    'ans4':'90%',
    'answer':'75%',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'13. The locomotory organ of Amoeba is?',
    'ans1':'Pseudopodia',
    'ans2':'Parapodia',
    'ans3':'Flagella',
    'ans4':'Cilia',
    'answer':'Pseudopodia',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'14. An instrument for measuring blood pressure is called?',
    'ans1':'Barometer',
    'ans2':'Spirometer',
    'ans3':'Sphygmomanometer',
    'ans4':'Haemocytometer',
    'answer':'Sphygmomanometer',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'15. The number of chromosomes present in a normal human being is?',
    'ans1':'23',
    'ans2':'22',
    'ans3':'46',
    'ans4':'48',
    'answer':'46',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'16. The disease that is caused by the virus is?',
    'ans1':'Typhoid',
    'ans2':'Cholera',
    'ans3':'Common Cold',
    'ans4':'Tetanus',
    'answer':'Common Cold',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'17. Where Sarthi classes is located',
    'ans1':'Murarpur',
    'ans2':'Station road',
    'ans3':'Kathari road gaya',
    'ans4':'Karimganj',
    'answer':'Kathari road gaya',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'18. Who is the best teacher in Sarthi classes',
    'ans1':'Rajiv sir',
    'ans2':'Monica mam',
    'ans3':'sudhanshu sir',
    'ans4':'chandan sir',
    'answer':'Rajiv sir',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'19. Who is Narendra damodar das modi',
    'ans1':'Prime minister of India',
    'ans2':'President of India',
    'ans3':'YouTuber',
    'ans4':'Doctor',
    'answer':'Prime minister of India',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'simple'
  },
  {
    'question':'20. Which exam is held for take admissions in IIT',
    'ans1':'jee mains',
    'ans2':'Neet',
    'ans3':'jee advance',
    'ans4':'jee mains and advance',
    'answer':'jee mains and advance',
    'class': 'active',
    'class2': 'endBtn'
  }
]